Ishtiaq Mahmood Amin

ANDROID / REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A-6, 543, East Kazipara, Mirpur-1216, Dhaka, Bangladesh

□ (+880) 1781-106123 | 💌 i4idrhine@gmail.com | 🖸 IronBlossom | 😩 IronBlossom | 🕲 iron_blossom | 🗖 IshtiaqMahmood_Amin

"The true delight is in the finding out rather than in the knowing."

Summary_

Current Android/React Native Developer at Offshore Software Development company Adaptive Enterprise Limited. Analytical and detail oriented programmer specialized in the android development, socket programming and both Object-oriented & Functional programming paradigm. A reader and a football fanatic who loves Linux, android kernel customization and enjoys tweaking the development environment to its efficiency. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience _____

Adaptive Enterprise Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec. 2014 - Present

- Provisioned an easily managable hybrid infrastructure (Amazon AWS + On-premise) utilizing IaC (Infrastructure as Code) tools like Ansible, Packer and Terraform.
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on CircleCI for containerized applications using Docker, AWS ECR and Rancher.
- Designed an overall service architecture and pipelines of the Machine Learning based Fashion Tagging API SaaS product with the micro-services architecture.
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js Koa and in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.
- Deployed a centralized logging environment (ELK, Filebeat, CloudWatch, S3) which gather log data from docker containers and AWS resources.
- Deployed a centralized monitoring environment(Grafana, InfluxDB, CollectD) which gather system metrics as well as docker run-time metrics.

Cloudwell Limited Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- Developed easy-to-use Android apps for the startup, facilitating Paywell's Payment infrastructure from Paywell Services app to in-house applications e.g. Paywell Distributor/Dealer/Collector/Territory Officer app.
- Provisioned backend developers with Servlet +php/Java bridge +Quartz Job Scheduler, by building an app that acts as tiny sms server for TeleTalk REB Bill Payment.
- Java Desktop application (jdk1.6+JavaFX) that pushes sms utilizing SilverStreet sms gateway.
- Worked with Telpo and partially developed Paywell application (with the provided SDK on Embedded-C) on 3 different embedded subsystem POS terminals (TPS300, KMY801B, MIL300)

AnnaNovas IT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ANDROID)

Oct. 2011 - Jun. 2013

- Built several apps using REST api, sqlite, custom views/controls, Google Maps API (v1), FCM/GCM(then Google C2DM) etc from ground up.
- Developed 3 inbuilt system apps and the launcher app that executes Linux shell commands for Polaroid Kids Tablet.

Professional Projeccts _____

Adaptive Enterprise Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2011

• Completed graduation with CGPA 2.97 from CSE Dept.

Education

AUST(Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2011

• Completed graduation with CGPA 2.97 from CSE Dept.

Presentation

DevFest Seoul by Google Developer Group Korea

Seoul, S.Korea

PRESENTER FOR < HOSTING WEB APPLICATION FOR FREE UTILIZING GITHUB, NETLIFY AND CLOUDFLARE>

Nov. 2017

- · Introduced the history of web technology and the JAM stack which is for the modern web application development.
- Introduced how to freely host the web application with high performance utilizing global CDN services.

6th CodeEngn (Reverse Engineering Conference)

Seoul, S.Korea

PRESENTER FOR < DEFCON 20TH: THE WAY TO GO TO LAS VEGAS>

Jul. 2012

· Introduced CTF(Capture the Flag) hacking competition and advanced techniques and strategy for CTF

Writing____

A Guide for Developers in Start-up

Facebook Page

FOUNDER & WRITER

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

• Drafted daily news for developers in Korea about IT technologies, issues about start-up.

Extracurricular Activity

PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

- Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- · Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.